Suicidal impulse_MK
I have insomnia due to hypersensitivity.
I suffer from PMS for a third of the month with depression, lethargy, fatigue,
mood swings, declined concentration, irritation, anger, and so on.
In times of severe stress, I've had occasions of suicidal impulses.
What can I do at these times?
Don't die. What else?
Then what should I do when in misery?
Let's say you pass by a shop, and seeing an expensive item,
you feel the impulse to steal it.
What should you do? Steal it? Or should you not despite the urge?
I shouldn't steal it.
A cute guy walks by,
and you feel the impulse to hug and kiss him.
Should you control yourself or do what you want to do?
I should control myself.
Then when you feel the urge to jump off a building, should you do it or control yourself?
There you go then.
Are there times when we all get certain urges?
Yes, there are.
There are.
But we control ourselves as it will be a loss for us not to.
We'll get humiliated by hugging a stranger.
We'll end up in jail for stealing something.
Have you seen today's news?
The head of IMF attempted to rape a hotel maid.
She came into the room to clean, and he tried to rape her.
See how he has been humiliated.
These examples show us whether to act on such impulses or not.
So do you go to a hospital?
I'm taking a sedative for the nerves.
You need to get treated at a hospital.
You're beyond the point of getting better by practicing Buddhism.
Get treated by a specialist doctor at the hospital.
But that won't necessarily cure you completely.
Your current conditions are rather severe.
Are you sleeping well?
Do you need sleeping pills?
Then that's a bit severe.
You should follow the doctor's advice
and not try to treat it on your own.
And remember that they are only impulses.
When you feel the urge to jump, should you?
I shouldn't.
At that moment, don't focus too much on thinking "I shouldn't die."
Think of something else.
There's a story.
A man went up a mountain to hang himself.
He had a noose tied around his neck.
Then he heard a tiger roar, so he ran the hell away to save himself.
His impulse to kill himself disappeared instantly.
You only need to let that one moment pass.
Impulses are momentary, just like when you see a stranger and think, 'Should I date him?'
Let that moment pass and it becomes okay.
It's like when you see something you want and feel the urge to steal it.
Apparently women experiencing PMS may have such impulses.
Let that moment pass and it becomes okay.
When the impulse to die hits, just let the moment pass.
I heard a story through someone I know.
A man went up a mountain to kill himself. As he was about to take his pills,
somebody walked by.
So he waited until that person passed,
but then another person walked by.
He waited again.
The person passed by, so he attempted to take the pills.
But then came a bicycle.
'Darn it, should I take it or not.
I'll wait, the bicycle should pass by fast enough', he thought.
He waited again.
But then this person gets off his bicycle
and starts walking as he can't ride it uphill.
(Audience laugh)
So the suicidal guy ended up waiting and waiting.
He eventually gave up and came back with pills in hand.
That's how the story goes.
So just let that moment pass.
You are having difficulty in controlling your momentary impulses.
Most cases of sexual assaults are a result of being unable to control such momentary impulses.
There was an incident where a principal was humiliated for fondling a student in a subway.
Bad consequences follow
when a person can't control these momentary impulses.
You have signs of this.
So do continue to take your medicine.
Do you work?
Yes, I do.
Can you work with your conditions?
I took a leave of absence, but I returned to work.
Isn't it difficult for you?
There are difficult times, but I rely on my medicine.
When I'm okay, I'm fine for a few days…
Do you live with your family or alone?
I live with my mom.
How would your mom feel if you killed yourself due to a momentary impulse?
She'll be in pain. I shouldn't do that.
Do you get along with your colleagues at work?
I don't really get along, but talk to them when necessary.
Reduce your time alone, okay?
Come to this temple to attend dharma talks, do volunteer work,
or start chatting with your colleagues.
Reduce your time alone, and don't think too much.
Do you work on Saturdays?
Some Saturdays I do.
Then on free weekends, go do some physical work.
We have a Jungto farm out in the countryside
where we work to remove weeds, till the soil, and lots more.
You can work all day there
and completely exhaust yourself,
drink a bit of rice wine as medicine, and then you'll sleep well.
If you do lots of physical labor,
you'll think less and sleep better.
You think too much not because you want to, but because thoughts come to you.
So when you find yourself thinking too much, just go outside.
Shake it off, take a bath,
go walk it off, and don't dwell in your head.
You keep falling into too much thought.
Don't keep sinking into too much thought.
Get out of your own head.
Think lightly.
Don't give meaning to every little thing.
If you live like that, you'll get better.
But for now, you should continue your medication.
Prostration should be good.
Try 300 bows every morning.
Do it at night if you can't in the morning.
Will you do it?
Yes.
Try it.
You will avoid dying with 300 bows a day.
You have to get healthy.
And even if you meet a great guy and he begs you to marry him,
don't get married now.
Now is not the right time.
(Audience laugh)
You shouldn't get married just yet.
But if you do, don't have a baby right now.
It will pass on to the baby.
Get well first. Then you can have a baby.